Contact

EUAN SCOTT-WATSON

Email: euan.scott-watson19@imperial.ac.uk

Mobile: 07734 436069 Nationality: British/French

Address: 2 Normand Gardens, Greyhound Road, Fulham, London, W14 9SB.

Github: github.com/EuanScottWatson - Please enquire for access tokens to private GitHub repositories

KEY SKILLS

Keen interest in Blockchain, Machine Learning and travelling the world.

Proficient in: Python, Swift, Hack, React, Kotlin and Java Good experience in: SQL, C, C++, Haskell and Prolog

Project management experience: GitHub, Mercurial, Jira and Trello

Database management experience: Google's Firebase and Cloud Functions; Meta's Dataswarm, Presto and Scuba

Fluent in **English** and **French**. Beginner in **Italian**.

EDUCATION

IMPERIAL COLLEGE LONDON

Oct 2019 - June 2023

MEng Computing with Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning Passed first, second and third year with **First Class Honours**.

- 92% compiler group project: built a compiler for ARM11 in Kotlin
- 90% first year group project: a **neural network** that could predict stocks optimised with a **genetic algorithm** to pick the best hyperparameters built from <u>scratch in C</u>
- 83% operating system group project: built an x86 architecture **OS** in C

ST GEORGE'S COLLEGE WEYBRIDGE

SEP 2012 - JULY 2019

An academic scholar since the age of 11

4 A-Levels:

Maths: A* · Further Maths: A* · Physics: A* · Computing: A

Extended Project Qualification: A*

7,500 word dissertation and presentation on the potentials of **Blockchain** in the healthcare industry.

<u>GCSEs:</u> 11 A*s

I was awarded the top honour of the college, the Headmistress' Prize for Outstanding Academic Achievement.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer @ Meta, LONDON

March 2022 - Sep 2022

6 month intern working within the Classification DevX team, maintaining the Omega Rule engine - an Integrity classification rule engine built in Hack, detecting abuse using heuristic rules, ML classifiers, and other features from various data sources.

- Set up a daily dataswarm pipeline to calculate a replayability score for every endpoint within the Omega Rule Engine
- Created a central "Omega Hub" tool for over 35 teams across Meta to use to help maintain and debug all Omega endpoints
- Had meetings with Omega customers to introduce and discuss these new metrics; including a business trip to Meta HQ in Menlo Park, California
- Languages utilised: Python, Javascript, Hack, Haskell and SQL
- Technologies utilised: Dataswarm, Scuba, Presto, Chronos and Mercurial

President @ Imperial Junior Solutions Ltd, LONDON

March 2022 - Oct 2022

International Manager @ IJS, LONDON

April 2021 - March 2022

Junior Enterprise based in London providing technical services and consulting to commercial clients.

- Founding the first UK Confederation with junior enterprises across the UK
- Managing current and creating new international relations with other enterprises in Europe for the potential of collaborative projects
- Delegate for IJS to attend all Junior Enterprise Europe conferences and take part in quarterly voting
- Most recently, taking on the role of President to guide the junior enterprise and grow our connections internationally

Undergraduate Teaching Assistant @ ICL, LONDON

SEP 2021 - MARCH 2022

Asked to Tutor at my university due to great grades in my Algorithms Design and Analysis module.

- Personal programming tutor to 9 first year students
- Weekly hour-long tutorials helping them with their studies
- Mark weekly programming courseworks and provide detailed feedback

Developer @ The ChoralHub Ltd, LONDON

Nov 2020 - Sep 2021

A platform working to make music education more accessible for everyone.

- Worked with 3 other developers engaged in daily scrum meetings and epic planning
- Expanded the serverless backend infrastructure through Python scripts running on Google Cloud
- Developed the iOS beta version of <u>Tchzant</u> in **Swift** after learning the language in two weeks
- Researched different deep learning techniques for frequency analysis and **NLP** for lyric recognition

Tutor @ MyTutor, LONDON

Feb 2020 - June 2021

Remote tutoring website for all ages

- Maths, Computing theory and programming tutor
- GCSE and A-Level students

OTHER INTERESTS

Sport: CMAS 3* Dive Master up to 60m depth

Charity and Volunteering Work:

- Founded and ran a weekly Maths Society in my college (2018-2019)
- Member of a weekly evening club for mentally disabled adults for two years (2017-2019)
- Weekly French lessons for elderly residents of my local care home (2016)